

joshua.a.abrams@gmail.com
(847) 636-6440
https://www.linkedin.com/in/joshua-a-abrams/
http://uxdesignportfol.io
Chicago, IL

I'm so glad that I have found the beautiful cross-section between tech and design. Since my childhood days on Geocities, I've been designing and coding websites for the world to see and I'm eager to bring my tech experience and design skills to the table in my new career. I am proud to be creating solutions in my field and intend to do so for many years to come.

### SKILLS

Design Tools: Sketch, Invision, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop

Programming Languages: Javascript, C#, Ruby

Version Control: Git, TFS

Web Technologies: ASP.net MVC, Ruby on Rails, React, React Native, HTML5, CSS, JSON, XML

Industries: Finance, Healthcare, Warehouse Logistics, Medicine, Law

# **PROJECTS**

### ShoppingGives / ChangeCommerce (Ongoing)

Performing research and synthesis for an ongoing project to benefit non-profit organizations. Working with a small team with the intent of refining the design of a Shopify application.

## Transit Talk (Ongoing)

Working as a UX designer on a crowd-sourced issue-reporting platform for public transit systems.

## Bartleby's Ice Cream Cakes

Upgraded and redesigned an e-commerce platform for a local, woman-owned food startup. Coded a new Shopify site and coordinated its launching.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# ShoppingGives

October 2019 - Present

### UX Designer and Researcher (Intern)

Working in a small team of three on research and design for a small startup. Conducting competitive analysis, heuristic evaluations, user Interviews, and contextual inquiries. Synthesizing affinity maps, site maps, user personas, and journey maps.

# **General Assembly**

July 2019 - September 2019

UX Design Fellow

Worked in solo and group capacities to deliver high quality research and design for web and mobile applications. Exercised Agile and Waterfall methodologies in a fast paced, quickly changing environment. Worked with cutting edge UX design strategies and technologies.

### SPR Consulting

**April 2016 - February 2019** 

# Software Engineering Consultant

Developed complex web solutions in a professional technical consulting environment. Responsible for building and maintaining client application solutions.

# **EDUCATION**

General Assembly - Chicago, IL
UX Design Immersive
Dev Bootcamp - Chicago, IL
Web Development Immersive

July 2019 - September 2019

September 2019 - January 2019